Dawn Sheedy (she/they)

Software Engineer with several years of experience specializing in web application development. I take pride in writing clean, documented, and reusable code. I love taking on challenges and working with individuals who share my passion for technology.

Seattle, WA https://dawnsheedy.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Clearwater Analytics, Seattle — L2 Software Development Engineer

July 2022 - Present

Quickly got up to speed and learned required technologies (Java Libraries, Angular). Led a training on Angular. Pushed for more thorough documentation for code and tickets. Wrote new and overhauled existing code to be modular, readable, and well-documented. Planned and initiated a common React component library for internal applications. Consistently provided accurate time estimates for tasks.

Press Hook, Remote — Full-Stack Engineer

September 2021 - July 2022

Worked as a vital early developer in a fast-paced startup environment. Integral part of a transition to utilizing React for FE interfaces. Architected and implemented a custom real-time messaging system. Implemented CI/CD processes. Contributed to improving internal documentation. Screened and interviewed candidates. Assisted internal non-technical employees with issues.

Kinstone, LLC, Remote — Volunteer Software Developer

August 2016 - February 2022

Worked with an international team of volunteers to provide an interactive, engaging experience for thousands of concurrent viewers. Utilized 3rd party APIs to deliver projects including a chat bot that integrated with other in-house systems. Provided rapid prototypes to prove concepts, including a live closed captioning utility.

EDUCATION

Virginia Commonwealth University, Virginia — Computer Science

August 2019 - December 2021 (Incomplete due to reasons unrelated to performance)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript/Typescript

- React & Redux
- Angular
- Node

HTML/CSS

C#

Unity

Java

Pvthon

SQL (MS, Postgres, etc.)

CI/CD (Jenkins, GHA, etc.)

System Architecture

Microservices

Testing

Docker

Git

BUSINESS SKILLS

Agile Process

Skill Acquisition/Self-teaching

Collaborating

Communication

Assisting/Training Others

Time Estimation/Planning

PROJECTS

Contract Work — Python (Django), Azure, React

Created a utility for creating and automatically scoring mental health assessments.

Unity Jubeat Rewrite — Unity, C#, Node

Wrote my own version of the Japanese arcade game *Jubeat* using unity targeting the iPad. This was an exercise to learn Unity, improve my C# skills, and generally become more well rounded.

Personal Website — React/CSS

Used React, React-Router, HTML, and CSS to create a landing page that is distinct and related to my interests and aesthetics.

DDRLights - C++, Arduino, Electronics

Forked Stepmania, an open source rhythm game, and modified it to generate automated light patterns based on stepfiles. Original version utilized stage lights controlled via the DMX protocol.

Forza Telemetry Viewer — Go, React, Websockets

Created a user interface for displaying current vehicle information from Forza Horizon telemetry data. Intended for use as a stream overlay.

Elite: Dangerous Alexa Control — Python, AWS

Wrote an Alexa skill for personal use that allowed voice control for many aspects of Elite: Dangerous. (e.g. "Alexa, tell ship to deploy landing gear" -> deploys landing gear in-game)

Virtual Dance Pad — Python, Oculus SDK

Wrote a basic application that converted VR controller positions in defined spaces to key inputs. For the purpose of zip-tying controllers to my shoes and playing DDR.

Collaborative Captioning App — Websockets, Node, React

Wrote a proof of concept application for aggregating captions written by multiple people and pushing them into a twitch livestream. Ended up being scrapped due to typing speed requiring stenographers.

Sprinterface — Raspberry Pi, Node, HTML/CSS/JS

Wrote a basic interface for a family member for them to control the lights/other electronics in their Sprinter van using a tablet.